Changkun Ou, Ph.D.

Online version: https://changkun.de/s/resume

Last updated: September 18, 2023

Resume

@changkun 🞧

changkun.de

Introduction

I received a Ph.D. in the field of human-computer interaction at the Institute of Informatics, LMU Munich (Germany). My <u>research</u> explore design tradeoffs on intelligent human-in-the-loop systems and develops machine learning algorithms to support user decision-making processes. In context, I employee efficient and robust engineering practices to design and implement systems that deliver actual impact to real users.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. Media Informatics (Dr. rer. nat.)

Feb. 2019 - Apr. 2023

LMU Munich

Munich, Germany

- Thesis: "The Intelligence in the Loop: Empirical Explorations and Reflections", Magna cum Laude
- Thesis Committee: Prof. Dr.-Ing. Andreas Butz (Erstberichterstatter), Prof. Dr. Eyke Hüllermeier (Zweitberichterstatter), Prof. Dr.-Ing. Marc Stamminger (Drittberichterstatter).

Master Student Human-Computer Interaction (M.Sc.)

Oct. 2016 - Jan. 2019

LMU Munich; overall grade: 1.63 (max. 1.0) between "Very Good" and "Good"

Munich, Germany

- Thesis: "Understanding and Predicting Web Browsing Behavior"
- Advisors: Dr. Daniel Buschek, Dr. Malin Eiband, Prof. Dr. Heinrich Hußmann

Bachelor Student Computer Science and Engineering (B.Eng.)

Sep. 2012 - Jul. 2016

Southwest University for Nationalities; overall grade: 3.74 (max. 4.0), "Top 1" of 154 students

Chengdu, China

- Thesis: "Designing Alternative Contact-free Control Modalities for Smart Watches"
- Advisor: Prof. Dr. Yaxi Chen

RECENT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Development Engineer III (Senior)

Sep. 2022 - Present

Sixt SE

Munich Pullach, Germany

- As engineer: design and developing automated pricing system to support price decisions; making existing systems approx. 300x faster
- Involved techniques: Go; C++; Python; Kubernetes; Jenkins; Promethues; Postgres; Redis; AWS; etc.

Research Associate Aprl. 2018 – Mar. 2023

 $LMU\,Munich$

Munich, Germany

- As researcher: research on human-in-the-loop machine learning 3D graphics systems
- · As teacher: teach 12 classes (as lecturer/instructor/assistant/tutor), and supervising 20+ student theses and seminars
- As developer: develop a 3D mesh processing backend system in collaboration with industry partner WAY digital solutions; develop, migrate, and maintain a 17 year-old university CMS system, and a 13 year-old collaborative system

Backend Software Engineer (Remote)

Apr. 2018 – Jan. 2019

LabEx Technology Ltd

Munich, Germany

- **As team leader**: leading developments of an oversea product; established microservice based backend architecture; the product autoscales cloud instances (on AWS/AlibabaCloud) ranging from 20 to 200; the product user group grows from 5k+ to 30k+ during my incumbency.
- As developer: 1) developed a scalable remote desktop proxy (support WebSocket to VNC/RDP/SSH protocols) using Go; 2) developed an
 automated multi-cloud resource management microservice that abstracts cross cloud providers (supports AWS/AlibabaCloud over 15 cloud
 products, e.g., IAM/EC2/VPC/etc), scales and used by 10k+ users; 3) developed a kubernetes-like container and instance hybrid management
 service.
- Involved techniques: Frontend: Vue, jQuery, Webpack, Electron; Backend: Go, Cgo, Gin, Beego, gRPC, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, Hypervisor, Nginx, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, AlibabaCloud, etc

OPEN SOURCE ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS

I am enthusiastic about the open source movement and active in the Go community. A public statistics indicates that I have earned 20.8k+ stars, 14.9k+ total code commits, 20 contributed open source projects. A public contribution ranking indicates I am a **top-200** active user in Germany. See github.com/changkun for more authored softwares (including frameworks/tools). Here lists a few selected activities and organizations:

- Go (organization member): an open sourced programming language developed by a team at Google, and have approx. 2 million developer users in the globe. I am one of the official Go organization member (163 people in total), current maintainer of x/mobile repository, active contributor to language runtime and standard library.
- fyne (organization member): an open sourced cross platform GUI framework written in Go, and I am one of the organization member (12 people in total), mainly contributing to graphics and mobile drivers, performance improvements.
- The golang.design Initiative (founder): I created the organization. The organization currently hosts 25 software projects and 6 core members. The organization website have 465k+ page views and 66k+ historical viewers in total since Sep 2020.
- The TalkGo community (organization member): I am a core member of the organization. The community organizes weekly public tech talks, currently have 6.35k+ subscribers, organized 132 public talks. I contributed 7 talks, and they are one of the most viewed talks.
- Occasional contributions: Tensorflow (164+ stars), etcd (39.6k+ stars), etc.

EXPERTISE AND SKILLS

Expertise is context- and comparison-dependent. Here states the years of experience in terms of use, also indicates an estimation of the level of expertise (either *intermediate*, *experienced*, or *expert*):

- Domain: Computer graphics (3D rendering and geometry processing, 3 years of Bachelors level teaching at university, 2 years of Masters level teaching, Blender/OpenGL/Metal/three.js, experienced); Machine learning (1 year of Masters level teaching at university, Andrew Ng's Deep Learning Specialization Certificate (ID: QGH8ZVJ6J2L2), Sklearn/Tensorflow/PyTorch/etc, experienced); Data analysis (3 years of PhD research, numpy/seaborn/pandas/etc., experienced); Web development (2 years of industrial backend engineering, Go/React/etc., experienced).
- Language: Go (5 years+, expert); Python (4+ years, experienced); JavaScript/TypeScript (5+ years, experienced); C/C++ (2+ years, intermediate); ET_EX (10+ years, intermediate). I speak native Mandarin; fluent professional English; elementary German.

SCHOLARSHIPS AND AWARDS

ACM SIGCHI Gary Marsden Travel Awards Full Travel Support	Jan. 2023
ACM Symposium on Virtual Reality Software and Technology Best Paper Award	Nov. 2022
ACM SIGCHI Mensch und Computer Honorable Mention Award	Sep. 2022
ACM SIGCHI Special Recognitions (CHI '20) Outstanding Reviews	Nov. 2019
Siemens AILab Hackathon 2nd Winner	Nov. 2017 <i>Munich, Germany</i>
China National Scholarship University of Electronic Science and Technology of China	Sep. 2016 Chengdu, China
Excellent Bachelor Thesis Award Southwest University for Nationalities	Jun. 2016 Chengdu, China
Best University Graduates Award Sichuan Province	Jan. 2016 Chengdu, China
China National Scholarship Southwest University for Nationalities	Sep. 2014 Chengdu, China
Meritorious Winner in American Mathematical Contest in Modeling (MCM' 14) Southwest University for Nationalities	Apr. 2014 Chengdu, China